Hi there.
My name's Larry Omaha and I'm a professional stand up comedian.
How does one become a comedian?
One creates a lot of material.
Memorizes that material, rehearses it, refines it, performs it in front of strangers, every night sometimes and becomes so good that people want to pay to see them.
There is a lot more that goes on and involved with that.
It takes years to develop this material.
It takes years to develop what they call your persona, to develop the kind of material that works for your persona.
It involves going to open mikes.
Going to audition nights, going to audition nights, going to coffee houses, going to comedy clubs on their off nights and getting up in front of small crowds, sometimes two or three people and trying out that material.
But that's the only way you can become a comic and then grow in to becoming a full time professional comedian.
There's no other way around it.
There might be one person in a million who is born to be a comic and just got up on stage one day and was funny and never had to sweat, never had to pay dues.
But, I doubt it.
There's real no set education to become a comedian.
The education most comics have is street.
What they've learned in their life.
Education of living.
You certainly don't need a college education to become a good comic.
Some of the greatest comedians that we've had never made it past high school.
On the other hand, there are many great comics who did have a college education.
Everyone's going to be different.
You don't have to go to a comedy school.
Some people do.
It is not necessary.
You don't have to get any kind of technical specific certificate or anything like that.
It is really a learn on the job type of profession.
The way most of us do it is by going out every night to clubs and wait to get on that stage.
That stage time is really the most crucial thing to becoming a comic.
Without stage time, you'll never achieve, you will never grow, you'll never become a really good professional stand up comedian.